iadb.org 2019-04-03

# Privacy Policy | IADB

## **Introduction**

This Privacy Policy sets forth the data protection policies and practices of the web site of the Inter-American Development Bank, (“IDB”, “we” or “us”) generally denoted by the URL “iadb.org” and its lower level domains (the “ Web Site”). As explained in the IDB Terms of Use, into which this Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference, the IDB is an international organization established by its member countries pursuant to the Agreement Establishing the Inter-American Development Bank. For more information on the IDB, and the Web Site and its operations, please review carefully the IDB Terms of Use. Certain features or functions of the Web Site may now or in the future require your establishment of a user identification and acceptance of other or additional terms of use, which may also include different privacy policies.

By using the Web Site, you (“User”) are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy, including as they may be amended from time to time. Your use of the Web Site therefore constitutes your consent to our collection, use and disclosure of personal information we collect from you through the Web Site, as described herein. Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Policy before using the Web Site.

As the Web Site is updated and expanded, our Privacy Policy may change, so please review the posted Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you about material changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a notice on the Web Site or by sending you an e-mail (if you have provided us your e-mail address).

## **Scope and Definitions**

This Privacy Policy sets forth our policies and practices with respect to information concerning visitors to the Web Site, including how we collect, use, share and store that information. Although this Policy applies only to information collected through the Web Site, it is consistent with our policies and practices with respect to all personal information received by the IDB, whether in electronic, paper or verbal format.

As used in this Policy, the following terms have a specific meaning:

**Personally Identifiable Information**

PII is information that is about or pertains to a specific individual and can be linked to (identified with) that individual.

**Anonymous Information**

Aggregated information, demographic information and any other information that does not reveal the specific identity of an individual.

**An IP Address**

The Internet Protocol address of the computer an individual uses to access the Web Site (and the Internet more generally).

## **Collection of Information through the Web Site**

**Information You Submit**

We will collect PII you provide to us, such as if you send us an e-mail via the “Contact Us” page of the Web Site, or post information in shared areas of the Web Site. If we include features such as blogs, which permit the posting of comments or other material of a sort reasonably expected to be displayed on the Web Site and that will directly or indirectly include PII and such features are not subject to other terms and conditions and/or privacy policies, then you acknowledge and agree that any PII that you include in such comments or material may be publicly accessible and that we cannot control the manner in which others may use that PII.

**Information Automatically Collected**

When you visit the Web Site, certain Anonymous Information is automatically collected relating to that visit. The IDB web servers collect anonymous logs during user visits to the Web Site. This may be done through cookies, “clear GIFs” (a/k/a “web beacons,” or “pixel tags”), or similar technologies to retain information about you and your use of the Web Site.

Cookies are small data files that are sent to your browser or related software from a web server and stored on your computer or device. Cookies often include an anonymous unique identifier and track and store your user preferences while using the Web Site as well as technical information about your use of the Web Site.

Most web browsers can be set to inform you when a cookie has been sent to you and provide you with the opportunity to refuse that cookie. However, refusing a cookie may in some cases preclude you from using, or negatively affect the display or function of, the Web Site or certain areas or features of the Web Site. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.

We automatically collect data about your IP Address. Also, if you access the Web Site from a mobile or other device, your unique device identifier assigned to that device or other transactional information for that device may also be collected.

All of these technologies are designed to improve and personalize your experience using the Web Site. By using the Web Site, you consent to the use of the tracking technologies as described above.

**Use of Information Collected Through the Web Site**

We may use the PII we collect from you (as described above) to send you e-mail messages, mailings, other forms of communication or otherwise contact you in response to your requests. We also may use your PII to send you information that might interest you, such as descriptions of new projects, activities of IDB and other organizations, funding resources, etc. In addition, we may use your PII for recordkeeping purposes within the IDB, and we may combine the PII we collect from you with other information, including both PII and non-PII obtained from other sources, including other Users, for purposes of analysis relevant to the Web Site and the IDB’s objectives.

Where you have requested to receive e-mail updates from us, we may periodically send you emails that promote or otherwise contain information relating to the use of the Web Site and/or the IDB. When you receive an e-mail from us, you may indicate a preference to “opt out” of, and thus to stop receiving further e-mails from us, by following the “unsubscribe” instructions provided in the email(s) you received or sending us an “opt-out” request using the contact information provided below, as applicable.

We use the Anonymous Information we collect to analyze Web Site visitor behavior as a measure of interest in, and use of, the Web Site and of the various services we offer. This information is used to create aggregate statistics regarding, for example, when the Web Site is accessed, the pages which refer visitors to the Web Site, the type of web browsers visitors use, and which pages of the Web Site are viewed. These statistics help us understand how the Web Site is used and provide us with valuable information for improving the Web Site in the future.

## **Sharing of Information Collected Through the Web Site**

**Legal Obligation Disclosures**

We may disclose PII or other information collected through the Web Site in response to legal process or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, for example, in response to a court order, subpoena, or a law enforcement agency’s request. We also may disclose such information to protect the security and operation of the Web Site or the rights of other Web Site users, and to protect ourselves and our partners, affiliates, consultants, suppliers, and providers against liability, or if we have reason to believe that someone is causing or threatening to cause injury to or interference with the IDB’s rights or property, as well as to protect against fraud.

**Business Transfers**

In the event that the a portion of the IDB’s assets or operations is sold or assigned, merged with or otherwise transferred to a party other than the IDB, we may transfer your PII as part of the transaction. In the event such a transfer occurs, the IDB will use reasonable efforts to assure that your PII will remain subject to the same types of protection as it was prior to the transfer. However, once your PII is transferred in such a transaction, it will no longer be subject to this Privacy Policy, and you will need to review the policies and practices of the party receiving the information to learn about the protection then accorded to the PII.

**Updates to Personal Information**

In the event that you have provided us with PII, either through using one of the “contact us” methods on the Web Site, or through availing yourself of opportunities to include such information in blogs or similar features, you may request that we correct such PII, or delete it. For your protection, we will only implement such requests with respect to the PII associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request.

We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable, including a request for deletion of PII from our records. We may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, and there may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed.

Please note that we are not responsible for correcting, updating or deleting any PII information on the Web Site. We cannot control the use or retransmission of any PII that has already been retrieved by any visitor to the Web Site.

**Data Security**

We endeavor to protect the security and integrity of PII we collect by implementing physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction. However, due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that any information, whether during transmission through the Internet, while stored on our data systems or otherwise maintained by us, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers. This includes information provided to us by email, through direct postings on the Web Site, or through the “Contact Us” feature of the Web Site. In providing information through these channels, you should be aware that your transmission might not be secure while it is in transit, and that a third party could possibly view the information in transit.

**Data Retention**

We retain PII and Anonymous Information collected through the Web Site for operational, recordkeeping and legal purposes. We will retain PII about you for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Policy or our data retention policies, unless a longer retention period is required by law.

**International Data Transfers**

When you submit information to us through the Web Site or otherwise, that information (including any PII) will be processed in the United States. The data protection and other privacy laws of the United States may not afford the same level of protection as the laws of certain other countries. By providing personal information to IDB from outside the United States, whether directly or indirectly though the Web Site or otherwise, you expressly consent to the transfer of your information to the United States, in accordance with the measures of protection described in this Privacy Policy.

**Privacy of Children**

The Web Site is not directed at minors and we do not knowingly collect from or maintain any personal information regarding persons under the age of 13.

**Linked Services**

The Web Site may contain links to third-party websites. Our provision of a link to any other website or location is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. The IDB does not control the websites, applications or other services that are operated by third parties and we are not responsible for the data protection and privacy practices of these websites, applications or other services. Thus, we recommend that, once you access any such other web site, application or service, you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices governing that other website, application or service.

## **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy practices, you may contact us by: http://www.iadb.org/en/information-request,18885.html
